Guide to the Perspecta, School of Architecture, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Perspecta, School of Architecture, Yale University, records
1952-2002
1952-1973
RU 336
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
6.75
The records consist of editorial and financial correspondence, copyrights, reviews, architectural drawings, articles, accounting records, and photographs and negatives documenting the publication of Perspecta, a journal of the Yale School of Architecture (formerly the School of Architecture and Design and School of Art and Architecture).
Perspecta
Yale University. School of Architecture and Design
Yale University. School of Architecture
Yale University. School of Art and Architecture
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 19-E (YRG 19-E), Records of departments, offices, programs, and projects of the Yale School of Architecture.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of editorial and financial correspondence, copyrights, reviews, architectural drawings, articles, accounting records, and photographs and negatives documenting the publication of Perspecta, a journal of the Yale School of Architecture (formerly the School of Architecture and Design and School Art and Architecture).
Architecture; College publications; Photographs; Perspecta
- Records of Perspecta, 1952-1973; Accession 1990-A-161
  - Editorial Correspondence
    - Albers, Anni (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Arnheim, Rudolf (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Barnes, Edward L. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Belluschi, Pietro (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Bertois, Harry (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Bodiansky, Wlandimir (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Bunshaft, Gordon (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Burle-Marx, Roberto (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Candela, Felix (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Carver, Norman (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Catalano, Eduardo (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Churchill, Henry (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Clifford, Henry (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Drexler, Arthur (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Erskine, Ralph (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Fuller, Buckminster (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Gropius, Walter (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Harris, Mrs. Harwell Hamilton (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Hauer, Erwin (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Herve, Lucien (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Hicks, Sheila (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Hithcock, H.-R. (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Holden, Ruben A. (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Howe, George (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Izenour, George C. (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Johnson, Philip C. (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Jordy, William H. (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Kahn, Louis I. (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Kaufman, Edgar J., Jr. (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Kelly, Richard (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Kepes, Gyorgy (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Kubler, George (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Lambert, Phyllis B. (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Langer, Suzanne (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Loeb, Sidney S. Foundation (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Lundy, Victor (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - MacDonald, William (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Macomber, George B.H. Company (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Maritain, Jacques (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Meeks, C.L.V. (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Mendelsohn, Erich (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Moholy-Nagy, Sibyl (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Moore, Charles (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Morrison, Hugh (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Mumford, Lewis (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Nakashima, George (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Nelson, George (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Nelson, Paul (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - van der Rohe, Mies (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Financial Correspondence
    - Abel, Richard and Co., Inc. (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Angus and Robertson, Ltd. (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Architectural Forum (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Bailey Subscription (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Burgdorf, W.A. Bookseller (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Busck, Arnold (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - De Tjalk (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Ebsco Subscription Service (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Faxon, F.W. (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Flaxon, M. (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Fox, Joseph - Books (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Harvard Book Store (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Harvard Cooperative Society (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - International Book Service, Ltd. (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - International Periodicals (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - McGregor Magazine Agency (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Moore-Cottrell (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Popular Subscription (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Stechert Hafner, Inc. (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Tiranti, Alec, Ltd. (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Tokodo Shoten, Ltd. (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Universitas Periodicals (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Wittenborn and Co. (Box 2, Folder 72 - 74)
    - Yale Cooperative Corp. (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Zwemmer, A., Ltd. (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Volumes 9/10 - related material
    - Bibliography: vols. 1-14 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Biographical Data, Volume 1: See Box 9 Folder 192 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Volume 2: Copyright - Library of Congress, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Volume 4: Copyright - Library of Congress, 1957-58 (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Volume 5: Copyright - Library of Congress, 1958-59 (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - Volume 6: Copyright - Library of Congress, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - Volume 7: Copyright - Library of Congress, 1959-1960 (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - Copyright - Library of Congress, Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - 1957-1965
    - 1960, 1963-1964
    - Volume 8: Copyright - Library of Congress, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - Certificate from Type Director's Club, Photographs and Architectural Drawings: See Box 9 Folder 193, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - Volume 9/10: Editorial Correspondence; memos, 1965-1968 (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - Financial Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - Financial Notes, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 89)
    - Copyright - Library of Congress, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - Reviews: Architectural Drawings: See Box 9 Folder 194 Photographs: See also Box 9 Folder 195 (Box 3, Folder 91)
    - Rudolph Apartment (Box 3, Folder 92)
    - And Negatives (Box 3, Folder 93)
    - General (Box 3, Folder 94 - 95)
  - Volume 11: related material (Box 4)
    - 1965-1967 (Box 3, Folder 96 - 97)
    - 1967 (Box 3, Folder 98)
    - Miscellaneous, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 99)
    - Copyright - Library of Congress, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 100)
    - Bills: Financial Notes, 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 101)
    - 1966 (Box 3, Folder 102)
    - 1967 (Box 3, Folder 103)
    - Manuscripts (Box 3, Folder 104 - 107)
    - Memoranda; Lists; Table of Contents (Box 3, Folder 108)
  - Volume 11/12 - related material
    - Volume 11: "Amazing Archigrams" See also Box 9 Folder 196 (Box 5, Folder 109)
    - The Editors - Interview with Robert Theobald (Box 5, Folder 110)
    - Fuller, R. Buckminster - "Vision 65 Summary Lecture" (Box 5, Folder 111)
    - McHale, John - "World Dwelling" (Box 5, Folder 112)
    - McLuhan, Marshall - "The Invisible Environment: The Future of an Erosion" (Box 5, Folder 113)
    - Moore, Charles W. - "Plug it in Rameses and See if it Lights up" (Box 5, Folder 114)
    - Nelson, George - "Obsolescence" (Box 5, Folder 115)
    - Nodelman, Sheldon - "Sixties Art: Some Philosophical Perspectives" (Box 5, Folder 116)
    - Stirling, James - "Conversation With Students" (Box 5, Folder 117)
    - Vanderbeek, Stan - "Re:Vision" (Box 5, Folder 118)
    - Venturi, Robert - "3 Projects" (Box 5, Folder 119)
    - Wood, Shadrach and Vailland, Roger - "Conversation on Urbanism" (Box 5, Folder 120)
    - Miscellaneous Galleys (Box 5, Folder 121)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, Lists, Memos (Box 5, Folder 122)
    - Notes (Box 5, Folder 123)
    - Volume 11 and 12 Miscellaneous, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 124)
    - Volume 12, Editorial Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 125 - 126)
    - Parr, Albert Eide - "Democracy, Technology and Urban Design" (Box 5, Folder 127)
    - Fund, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 128 - 129)
    - Sales Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 130)
    - Bills, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 131)
    - Financial, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 132)
    - Correspondence Re: Back Issues 1-12 (Box 5, Folder 133)
  - Volume 13/14: related material
    - Letter to National Endowment for the Arts; Also Letters Appealing for Financial Support (Box 6, Folder 134)
    - Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 135 - 136)
    - 1972-1974 (Box 6, Folder 137 - 138)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 139 - 140)
    - Yale Press Production Cost, 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 141)
    - Bills, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 142)
    - Accounts Settled, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 143)
    - Invoices Filed, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 144)
    - Foreign Orders, 1969-1972 (Box 6, Folder 145)
    - Checks Received (xerox copies), 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 146)
    - Price Letter (Box 6, Folder 147)
    - Cover Letter for Return Manuscripts and Photographs (Box 6, Folder 148)
    - Vidler, Anthony - "The Industrial World: The Reconstruction of Urban Utopia in the Late 19thCentury France", 1970 (Box 6, Folder 149)
    - Monograph from Thomas W. Brown, Jr., 1974 (Box 6, Folder 150)
    - Coombs, Robert - Personal Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 151)
    - Applegate, Judith - "Paul Nelson: An Interview" (Box 7, Folder 152)
    - Aptaker, Neil - "Hoover Limited" (Box 7, Folder 153)
    - Coombs, Robert - "Norman Bel Geddes: Highways and Horizons" (Box 7, Folder 154)
    - Doremus, Thomas - "A Penthouse Way up in the Sky" and Zeppelin related material. (Box 7, Folder 155)
    - Ehramm, Jacques - "Habiter l'Utopie" (Box 7, Folder 156)
    - Eisenman, Peter D. - "The Casa del Fascio" (Box 7, Folder 157)
    - Gray, Eileen - "Two Houses and an Interior, 1926-1933" (Box 7, Folder 158)
    - Heron, Mike - "Have Mercy I Cry City" (Box 7, Folder 159)
    - Klutz, Heinrich - "Bertrand Goldberg" (Box 7, Folder 160)
    - Reprints (Box 7, Folder 161)
    - Korn, A., Fry, M. and Sharp, D. - "The M.A.R.S. Plan for London" (Box 7, Folder 162)
    - Leopold, Ellen - "QE II" (Box 7, Folder 163)
    - Nelson, Paul - Architectural Drawings for the Dinan Hospital (Box 7, Folder 164)
    - Nicoletti, Manfredi G. - "The End of Utopia" (Box 7, Folder 165)
    - Rowe, Colin and Slutzky, Robert - "Transparency" (Box 7, Folder 166)
    - Sharp, Dennis - "Park Meerwijk - An Expressionist Experiment in Holland" (Box 7, Folder 167)
    - Soleri, Paolo - "Utopia and/or Revolution" (Box 7, Folder 168)
    - Superstudio - "Holiday Machine" (Box 7, Folder 169)
    - Venturi, Robert - "Bijovoet and Duiker" (Box 7, Folder 170)
    - Wolf, Peter - "City Structuring and Social Sense in 19thand 20thCentury Urbanism" (Box 7, Folder 171)
    - Miscellaneous Page Proofs (Box 7, Folder 172)
    - Worksheets (Box 7, Folder 173)
  - Volume 15, miscellaneous
    - Architectural Drawings (Box 8, Folder 174)
    - Queen Elizabeth 2 - Photographs and Brochures (Box 8, Folder 175)
    - Shankin, Kirby - Drawings, Negatives and Positives (Box 8, Folder 176)
    - Photographs, See also Box 9 Folder 197 (Box 8, Folder 177)
    - Negatives, See also Box 9 Folder 198 Architectural Drawings, Photographs and Negatives, See: Folios (Box 8, Folder 178)
    - Volulme 15 - Distribution Lists, Miscellaneous (Box 8, Folder 179)
    - Blake and Neski Photographs, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 180)
    - Underground Newspaper - "New York Times" Spoof (Box 8, Folder 181)
    - Photographs, Unidentified (Box 8, Folder 182)
    - Subscription List (Box 8, Folder 183)
    - Business Forms (Box 8, Folder 184)
    - Printed Material, Oversize Items: See Box 9 Folder 199 (Box 8)
  - Oversize Material
    - Oversize Material - For Folder Descriptions Consult Inventory by Issue Number (Box 9, Folder 185 - 191)
    - Architectural drawings, photographs, negatives, transparencies (Box 10)
    - Architectural drawings, photographs, negatives, transparencies (cont'd) (Box 11)
- Harvard Design Magazine's review of Perspecta, 2002; Accession 2003-A-051
  - Harvard Design Magazine's review of Perspecta, 2002 (Box 1)